<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-09-24T10:23:14+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Diego Tuzi Website</title><subtitle>Diego Tuzi Telecomunication Engineer Personal Website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Seminar on “4G and 5G control signals, Stability analysis”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/05/24/unicas-electromagneticCompatibility_teaching1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seminar on “4G and 5G control signals, Stability analysis”" /><published>2021-05-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-11-11T20:07:19+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/05/24/unicas-electromagneticCompatibility_teaching1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/05/24/unicas-electromagneticCompatibility_teaching1.html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="teaching-activity-for-electromagnetic-compatibility-modelling-and-measurements-course">Teaching activity for “Electromagnetic Compatibility: Modelling and Measurements” course</h4>
<h5 id="university-of-cassino-and-southern-lazio">University of Cassino and Southern Lazio</h5>

<p>At the end of my master degree thesis, I introduced my thesis work to students of the course “Electromagnetic Compatibility: Modelling and Measurements” held by Prof. Domenico Capriglione during the Academic Year 2020/2021. It was an interesting experience and I was really happy to explain my thesis work and to answer to the student’s questions.
<img src="/assets/img/2021-05-24-unicas-electromagneticCompatibility_teaching1.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Thesis workflow image" /></p>

<p>Acquired and consolidated skills:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Human exposure to RF Fields (WHO/ICNIRP Guidelines, IEC measurement standards)</li>
  <li>NG-RAN, 5G New Radio (NR), 4G LTE</li>
  <li>5G Dynamic spectrum Sharing</li>
  <li>Lab Instruments: Network Scanner R&amp;S TSMA6, Spectrum Analyzer</li>
  <li>R&amp;S ROMES 4</li>
  <li>Matlab</li>
  <li>Python</li>
  <li>Libre Office Suite</li>
  <li>Public Speaking</li>
  <li>Presentation</li>
</ul>

<p>Resources:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2021-05-24-unicas-electromagneticCompatibility_teaching-5G.pdf">Presentation</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>dt</name></author><category term="Seminars for academic courses" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Teaching activity for “Electromagnetic Compatibility: Modelling and Measurements” course University of Cassino and Southern Lazio At the end of my master degree thesis, I introduced my thesis work to students of the course “Electromagnetic Compatibility: Modelling and Measurements” held by Prof. Domenico Capriglione during the Academic Year 2020/2021. It was an interesting experience and I was really happy to explain my thesis work and to answer to the student’s questions. Acquired and consolidated skills: Human exposure to RF Fields (WHO/ICNIRP Guidelines, IEC measurement standards) NG-RAN, 5G New Radio (NR), 4G LTE 5G Dynamic spectrum Sharing Lab Instruments: Network Scanner R&amp;S TSMA6, Spectrum Analyzer R&amp;S ROMES 4 Matlab Python Libre Office Suite Public Speaking Presentation Resources: Presentation]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Seminar on “EMF Human Exposure Measurements and Previsional Calculation for wireless systems”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/05/24/unicas-electromagneticCompatibility_teaching2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seminar on “EMF Human Exposure Measurements and Previsional Calculation for wireless systems”" /><published>2021-05-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-11-11T20:07:22+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/05/24/unicas-electromagneticCompatibility_teaching2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/05/24/unicas-electromagneticCompatibility_teaching2.html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="teaching-activity-for-electromagnetic-compatibility-modelling-and-measurements-course">Teaching activity for “Electromagnetic Compatibility: Modelling and Measurements” course</h4>
<h5 id="university-of-cassino-and-southern-lazio">University of Cassino and Southern Lazio</h5>

<p>At the end of my master degree thesis, I organized and conducted a little seminar on “EMF Human Exposure Measurements and Previsional Calculation for wireless systems”. I gave the seminar to “Electromagnetic Compatibility: Modelling and Measurements” students. I gave the seminar during the Academic Year 2020/2021. It was an interesting experience and I was really happy to explain part of my job and to answer to the student’s questions.
<img src="/assets/img/2021-05-24-unicas-electromagneticCompatibility_teaching2.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Thesis workflow image" /></p>

<p>Acquired and consolidated skills:</p>
<ul>
  <li>D. Lgs. n. 259 del 2003</li>
  <li>Italian regulations about Human Exposure to EMF</li>
  <li>Broadband EMF Exposure Measurements</li>
  <li>EMF Previsional Calculation</li>
  <li>EMLAB</li>
  <li>Public Speaking</li>
  <li>Presentation</li>
</ul>

<p>Resources:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2021-05-24-unicas-electromagneticCompatibility_teaching-aie.pdf">Presentation</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>dt</name></author><category term="Seminars for academic courses" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Teaching activity for “Electromagnetic Compatibility: Modelling and Measurements” course University of Cassino and Southern Lazio At the end of my master degree thesis, I organized and conducted a little seminar on “EMF Human Exposure Measurements and Previsional Calculation for wireless systems”. I gave the seminar to “Electromagnetic Compatibility: Modelling and Measurements” students. I gave the seminar during the Academic Year 2020/2021. It was an interesting experience and I was really happy to explain part of my job and to answer to the student’s questions. Acquired and consolidated skills: D. Lgs. n. 259 del 2003 Italian regulations about Human Exposure to EMF Broadband EMF Exposure Measurements EMF Previsional Calculation EMLAB Public Speaking Presentation Resources: Presentation]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">4G and 5G control signals: Stability analysis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/04/29/unicas-thesis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4G and 5G control signals: Stability analysis" /><published>2021-04-29T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-02-06T10:58:21+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/04/29/unicas-thesis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/04/29/unicas-thesis.html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="master-of-science-in-telecommunication-engineering">Master of Science in Telecommunication Engineering</h4>
<h5 id="university-of-cassino-and-southern-lazio---academic-year-20192020">University of Cassino and Southern Lazio - Academic Year 2019/2020</h5>

<p>As a student of University of Cassino and Southern Lazio, I ended my educational path with a thesis work entitled “4G and 5G control signals: Stability analysis”. I worked on the thesis for 8 months. I started with an extensive research part followed by an experimental part. I, Prof. G. Miele (my Supervisor) and Prof. D. Capriglione, Prof. M.D. Migliore and Prof. G. Cerro (my Co-Supervisors) had several meetings during the work to address the activities.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/2021-04-29_unicas_thesis_scenario2.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Thesis workflow image" /></p>

<p>It was an amazing experience. I’m very thankful to the Supervisors for received support and the availability during the thesis work.</p>

<p>Acquired and consolidated skills:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Human exposure to RF Fields (WHO/ICNIRP Guidelines, IEC measurement standards)</li>
  <li>NG-RAN, 5G New Radio (NR), 4G LTE</li>
  <li>5G Dynamic spectrum Sharing</li>
  <li>Lab Instruments: Network Scanner R&amp;S TSMA6, Spectrum Analyzer</li>
  <li>R&amp;S ROMES 4</li>
  <li>Matlab</li>
  <li>Python</li>
  <li>Libre Office Suite</li>
  <li>Zotero</li>
  <li>Gimp</li>
  <li>Blackmagic Davinci Resolve</li>
  <li>Scientific writing</li>
  <li>Public speaking</li>
  <li>Presentation</li>
</ul>

<p>Resources:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2021-04-29_unicas_master_thesis-slides.pdf">Thesis presentation</a></li>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2021-04-29_unicas_master_thesis.pdf">Thesis document</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://youtu.be/0GfSU4wAMzQ">Thesis video</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>dt</name></author><category term="Thesis works" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Master of Science in Telecommunication Engineering University of Cassino and Southern Lazio - Academic Year 2019/2020 As a student of University of Cassino and Southern Lazio, I ended my educational path with a thesis work entitled “4G and 5G control signals: Stability analysis”. I worked on the thesis for 8 months. I started with an extensive research part followed by an experimental part. I, Prof. G. Miele (my Supervisor) and Prof. D. Capriglione, Prof. M.D. Migliore and Prof. G. Cerro (my Co-Supervisors) had several meetings during the work to address the activities. It was an amazing experience. I’m very thankful to the Supervisors for received support and the availability during the thesis work. Acquired and consolidated skills: Human exposure to RF Fields (WHO/ICNIRP Guidelines, IEC measurement standards) NG-RAN, 5G New Radio (NR), 4G LTE 5G Dynamic spectrum Sharing Lab Instruments: Network Scanner R&amp;S TSMA6, Spectrum Analyzer R&amp;S ROMES 4 Matlab Python Libre Office Suite Zotero Gimp Blackmagic Davinci Resolve Scientific writing Public speaking Presentation Resources: Thesis presentation Thesis document Thesis video]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pspice simulations and Lab activities</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/12/unicas-ecs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pspice simulations and Lab activities" /><published>2020-06-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-11-11T20:07:14+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/06/12/unicas-ecs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/12/unicas-ecs.html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="course-reports-for-electronics-for-communication-systems">Course reports for “Electronics for Communication Systems”</h4>
<h5 id="university-of-cassino-and-southern-lazio---academic-year-20182019">University of Cassino and Southern Lazio - Academic Year 2018/2019</h5>

<p>As a student of University of Cassino and Southern Lazio, I realized several reports inside the master course “Electronics for Communication Systems” held by Prof. G. Busatto and Prof. C. Abbate.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/2020-06-12-unicas-ecs.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="lab-example" /></p>

<p>Acquired and consolidated skills:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://www.pspice.com/">Pspice</a></li>
  <li>Matlab</li>
  <li>Labs instruments: Power Supply, RF Signal Generator, Oscilloscope, Network Analyzer, Spectrum Analyzer</li>
  <li>Writing reports</li>
</ul>

<p>Resources:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_1_the_matching_network.pdf">The matching networks</a></li>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_2_cascode_amplifier.pdf">Wide band Cascode amplifier</a></li>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_3_lna.pdf">Low noise amplifier for FM receiver</a></li>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_4_tuned_amplifier_LO.pdf">Tuned amplifier with variable tuning frequency</a></li>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_5_LO.pdf">Design and PSPICE Simulation of the local oscillator</a></li>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_6_exp_LNA.pdf">Experimental Verification of a Low Noise Amplifier for FM receivers</a></li>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_7_exp_tuned_amplifier_LO.pdf">Experimental characterization of a tuned amplifier with variable tuning frequency</a></li>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_8_mixer.pdf">Design and PSPICE simulation of a Mixer</a></li>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_9_exp_mixer.pdf">Experimental characterization of a Low Noise Amplifier for FM receivers</a></li>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_10_exp_pll.pdf">Experimental characterization of the integrated PLL (HCF4046B)</a></li>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_11_classAB.pdf">Simulation of a class AB RF Power amplifier</a></li>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_12_exp_demFM.pdf">Experimental activity with a FM demodulator</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>dt</name></author><category term="Academic Projects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Course reports for “Electronics for Communication Systems” University of Cassino and Southern Lazio - Academic Year 2018/2019 As a student of University of Cassino and Southern Lazio, I realized several reports inside the master course “Electronics for Communication Systems” held by Prof. G. Busatto and Prof. C. Abbate. Acquired and consolidated skills: Pspice Matlab Labs instruments: Power Supply, RF Signal Generator, Oscilloscope, Network Analyzer, Spectrum Analyzer Writing reports Resources: The matching networks Wide band Cascode amplifier Low noise amplifier for FM receiver Tuned amplifier with variable tuning frequency Design and PSPICE Simulation of the local oscillator Experimental Verification of a Low Noise Amplifier for FM receivers Experimental characterization of a tuned amplifier with variable tuning frequency Design and PSPICE simulation of a Mixer Experimental characterization of a Low Noise Amplifier for FM receivers Experimental characterization of the integrated PLL (HCF4046B) Simulation of a class AB RF Power amplifier Experimental activity with a FM demodulator]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Spectrum Characterization and Occupancy Sensing (SCOS) application</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/13/unicas-imcs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spectrum Characterization and Occupancy Sensing (SCOS) application" /><published>2018-06-13T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-11-11T20:07:12+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/06/13/unicas-imcs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/13/unicas-imcs.html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="course-project-for-instrumentation-and-measurements-for-communication-systems">Course Project for “Instrumentation and Measurements for Communication Systems”</h4>
<h5 id="university-of-cassino-and-southern-lazio---academic-year-20182019">University of Cassino and Southern Lazio - Academic Year 2018/2019</h5>

<p>As a student of University of Cassino and Southern Lazio, I and other teammates developed this project inside the master course “Instrumentation and Measurements for Communication Systems” held by Prof. Gianfranco Miele.
The project is a “Spectrum Characterization and Occupancy Sensing (SCOS)” application. It uses two of Ettus USRP E310 (embedded SDR) controlled by GNU Radio and Matlab.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/2018-06-13-unicas-imcs.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="scos gui" /></p>

<p>Acquired and consolidated skills:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://www.gnuradio.org/">GNU Radio</a></li>
  <li>Software Defined Radio (SDR)</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.ettus.com/all-products/e310/">Ettus USRP E310</a></li>
  <li>Matlab GUI</li>
  <li>Presentation</li>
  <li>Teamwork</li>
  <li>Leadership</li>
</ul>

<p>Resources:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2018-06-03_unicas_imcs_scos_user_manual.pdf">SCOS User Manual</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>dt</name></author><category term="Academic Projects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Course Project for “Instrumentation and Measurements for Communication Systems” University of Cassino and Southern Lazio - Academic Year 2018/2019 As a student of University of Cassino and Southern Lazio, I and other teammates developed this project inside the master course “Instrumentation and Measurements for Communication Systems” held by Prof. Gianfranco Miele. The project is a “Spectrum Characterization and Occupancy Sensing (SCOS)” application. It uses two of Ettus USRP E310 (embedded SDR) controlled by GNU Radio and Matlab. Acquired and consolidated skills: GNU Radio Software Defined Radio (SDR) Ettus USRP E310 Matlab GUI Presentation Teamwork Leadership Resources: SCOS User Manual]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Coil Antenna design with Feko</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/05/19/unicas-arp.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coil Antenna design with Feko" /><published>2018-05-19T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-11-11T20:07:32+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/05/19/unicas-arp</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/05/19/unicas-arp.html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="course-project-for-antennas-and-radiowave-propagation">Course Project for “Antennas and Radiowave Propagation”</h4>
<h5 id="university-of-cassino-and-southern-lazio---academic-year-20182019">University of Cassino and Southern Lazio - Academic Year 2018/2019</h5>

<p>As a student of University of Cassino and Southern Lazio, I realized this project inside the master course “Antennas and Radiowave Propagation” held by Prof. M.D. Migliore.
The project is a “Coil Antenna design” using the Feko software.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/2018-05-29_unicas_arp_coil_antenna_project.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="webinar-keysight-wifi6" /></p>

<p>Acquired and consolidated skills:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Antenna Design</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.altair.com/feko/">Feko</a></li>
  <li>Matlab</li>
  <li>Writing reports</li>
</ul>

<p>Resources:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2018-05-29_unicas_arp_coil_antenna_project.pdf">Coil Antenna Design project</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>dt</name></author><category term="Academic Projects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Course Project for “Antennas and Radiowave Propagation” University of Cassino and Southern Lazio - Academic Year 2018/2019 As a student of University of Cassino and Southern Lazio, I realized this project inside the master course “Antennas and Radiowave Propagation” held by Prof. M.D. Migliore. The project is a “Coil Antenna design” using the Feko software. Acquired and consolidated skills: Antenna Design Feko Matlab Writing reports Resources: Coil Antenna Design project]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Unbundling the optical access with WDM-PONs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2014/02/01/polimi-unbundlingTheOpticalAccess.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unbundling the optical access with WDM-PONs" /><published>2014-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-10-28T14:28:54+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2014/02/01/polimi-unbundlingTheOpticalAccess</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2014/02/01/polimi-unbundlingTheOpticalAccess.html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="collaboration-with-dipartimento-di-elettronica-informazione-e-bioingegneria-deib">Collaboration with Dipartimento di Elettronica, Informazione e Bioingegneria (DEIB)</h4>
<h5 id="politecnico-di-milano---academic-year-20132014">Politecnico di Milano - Academic Year 2013/2014</h5>

<p>As a student and graduand of Politecnico di Milano, I started a collaboration with Dipartimento di Elettronica, Informazione e Bioingegneria (DEIB) and in particular with Prof. Guido Maier. 
This work was carried out in the context of a national project called “Rete Ottica di Accesso e Divisione di frequenza e/o di lunghezza d’onda per soluzioni Next Generation Network (ROAD-NGN)”. My contribution was about a cost-effective deployment of the optical access network for broadband operators. In particular I proposed a technique to perform the Unbundling in the Local Loop (ULL) when Passive Optical Networks (PONs) are deployed in the access.
I worked on this project from April 2013 to February 2014.  My final goal was to use this project to realize my master degree thesis at Politecnico di Milano. Unfortunately for personal reasons I couldn’t conclude my master degree at Politecnico di Milano.
Despite that, I enjoyed that time. Thanks to DEIB and in particular to Prof. Guido Maier, I acquired some useful skills regarding the scientific production. I realized several documents but I hadn’t the opportunity to publish the outcome of my work on a scientific magazine.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/2014-02-01-polimi-unbundlingTheOpticalAccess.JPG" class="img-fluid" alt="2014-02-01-polimi-unbundlingTheOpticalAccess" /></p>

<p>Acquired and consolidated skills:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Passive Optical Networks (PONs)</li>
  <li>CWDM and DWDM grids</li>
  <li>Optimization algorithms: Minimum Cost (MC) and Maximal Fairness (MF)</li>
  <li>Optical fibers</li>
  <li>AMPL Modeling Language</li>
  <li>Matlab</li>
  <li>Microsoft Office</li>
  <li>Scientific writing</li>
  <li>Public speaking</li>
</ul>

<p>Resources:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2014-02-01-polimi-unbundlingTheOpticalAccess-proposal.pdf">Complete proposal</a></li>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2014-02-01-polimi-unbundlingTheOpticalAccess-paper_draft1.pdf">First paper draft (not published)</a></li>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2014-02-01-polimi-unbundlingTheOpticalAccess-poster.pdf">FOTONICA 2014 Poster</a></li>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2014-02-01-polimi-unbundlingTheOpticalAccess-paper_draft2.pdf">Second paper draft (not published)</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>dt</name></author><category term="Academic Projects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Collaboration with Dipartimento di Elettronica, Informazione e Bioingegneria (DEIB) Politecnico di Milano - Academic Year 2013/2014 As a student and graduand of Politecnico di Milano, I started a collaboration with Dipartimento di Elettronica, Informazione e Bioingegneria (DEIB) and in particular with Prof. Guido Maier. This work was carried out in the context of a national project called “Rete Ottica di Accesso e Divisione di frequenza e/o di lunghezza d’onda per soluzioni Next Generation Network (ROAD-NGN)”. My contribution was about a cost-effective deployment of the optical access network for broadband operators. In particular I proposed a technique to perform the Unbundling in the Local Loop (ULL) when Passive Optical Networks (PONs) are deployed in the access. I worked on this project from April 2013 to February 2014. My final goal was to use this project to realize my master degree thesis at Politecnico di Milano. Unfortunately for personal reasons I couldn’t conclude my master degree at Politecnico di Milano. Despite that, I enjoyed that time. Thanks to DEIB and in particular to Prof. Guido Maier, I acquired some useful skills regarding the scientific production. I realized several documents but I hadn’t the opportunity to publish the outcome of my work on a scientific magazine. Acquired and consolidated skills: Passive Optical Networks (PONs) CWDM and DWDM grids Optimization algorithms: Minimum Cost (MC) and Maximal Fairness (MF) Optical fibers AMPL Modeling Language Matlab Microsoft Office Scientific writing Public speaking Resources: Complete proposal First paper draft (not published) FOTONICA 2014 Poster Second paper draft (not published)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Seminar on “Simulation for networks with input buffer”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/11/29/polimi-switchingrouting_teaching.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seminar on “Simulation for networks with input buffer”" /><published>2013-11-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-11T20:07:29+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2013/11/29/polimi-switchingrouting_teaching</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2013/11/29/polimi-switchingrouting_teaching.html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="teaching-activity-for-switching-and-routing-course">Teaching activity for “Switching and Routing” course</h4>
<h5 id="politecnico-di-milano---academic-year-20132014">Politecnico di Milano - Academic Year 2013/2014</h5>

<p>As a student and graduand of Politecnico di Milano, I gave a seminar about the C++ network simulator that I developed for the master course “Switching and Routing” held by Prof. Achille Pattavina during the Academic Year 2010/2011. I gave the seminar to the Switching and Routing’s students during the Academic Year 2013/2014.
It was an interesting experience and I was really happy to explain my work and to answer to the student’s questions.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/2013-11-29-polimi-switchingrouting-teaching.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="2013-11-29-polimi-switchingrouting-teaching" /></p>

<p>Acquired and consolidated skills:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Switching algorithms (Unfair, modN, localFifo, globalFifo, iRRM, iSLIP, FIRM)</li>
  <li>Head of line (HOL) blocking</li>
  <li>Microsoft Visual Studio IDE</li>
  <li>C++</li>
  <li>Microsoft Office Suite</li>
  <li>Presentation</li>
  <li>Public speaking</li>
</ul>

<p>Resources:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2013-11-29-polimi-switchingrouting-teaching.pdf">Presentation</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>dt</name></author><category term="Seminars for academic courses" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Teaching activity for “Switching and Routing” course Politecnico di Milano - Academic Year 2013/2014 As a student and graduand of Politecnico di Milano, I gave a seminar about the C++ network simulator that I developed for the master course “Switching and Routing” held by Prof. Achille Pattavina during the Academic Year 2010/2011. I gave the seminar to the Switching and Routing’s students during the Academic Year 2013/2014. It was an interesting experience and I was really happy to explain my work and to answer to the student’s questions. Acquired and consolidated skills: Switching algorithms (Unfair, modN, localFifo, globalFifo, iRRM, iSLIP, FIRM) Head of line (HOL) blocking Microsoft Visual Studio IDE C++ Microsoft Office Suite Presentation Public speaking Resources: Presentation]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Long Reach PON Survey</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2013/09/01/polimi-longReachPON.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Long Reach PON Survey" /><published>2013-09-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-11-11T19:48:11+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2013/09/01/polimi-longReachPON</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2013/09/01/polimi-longReachPON.html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="collaboration-with-dipartimento-di-elettronica-informazione-e-bioingegneria-deib">Collaboration with Dipartimento di Elettronica, Informazione e Bioingegneria (DEIB)</h4>
<h5 id="politecnico-di-milano---academic-year-20132014">Politecnico di Milano - Academic Year 2013/2014</h5>

<p>As a student and graduand of Politecnico di Milano, I started a collaboration with Dipartimento di Elettronica, Informazione e Bioingegneria (DEIB) and in particular with Prof. Guido Maier. During this collaboration I realized a survey on the Long Reach PON.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/2013-09-01-polimi-longReachPON.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="2013-09-01-polimi-longReachPON" /></p>

<p>Acquired and consolidated skills:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Passive Optical Networks (PONs)</li>
  <li>Long Reach PON</li>
  <li>Optical fibers</li>
  <li>Matlab</li>
  <li>Microsoft Office</li>
  <li>Scientific writing</li>
</ul>

<p>Resources:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2014-02-01-polimi-unbundlingTheOpticalAccess-proposal.pdf">Survey</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>dt</name></author><category term="Academic Projects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Collaboration with Dipartimento di Elettronica, Informazione e Bioingegneria (DEIB) Politecnico di Milano - Academic Year 2013/2014 As a student and graduand of Politecnico di Milano, I started a collaboration with Dipartimento di Elettronica, Informazione e Bioingegneria (DEIB) and in particular with Prof. Guido Maier. During this collaboration I realized a survey on the Long Reach PON. Acquired and consolidated skills: Passive Optical Networks (PONs) Long Reach PON Optical fibers Matlab Microsoft Office Scientific writing Resources: Survey]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Android Bluetooth Ranging</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2012/07/27/polimi-scni.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Android Bluetooth Ranging" /><published>2012-07-27T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-11-11T20:07:10+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2012/07/27/polimi-scni</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2012/07/27/polimi-scni.html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="course-project-for-localization-navigation-and-smart-mobility">Course Project for “Localization Navigation and Smart Mobility”</h4>
<h5 id="politecnico-di-milano---academic-year-20112012">Politecnico di Milano - Academic Year 2011/2012</h5>

<p>As a student of Politecnico di Milano, I and other teammates developed this project inside the master course “Localization Navigation and Smart Mobility” held by Prof. Monica Nicoli.
The project is an Android application. It estimates the distance between mobile terminals doing bluetooth measurements.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/2012-07-27-polimi-scni.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="android ranging image" /></p>

<p>Acquired and consolidated skills:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Localization systems</li>
  <li>Bluetooth</li>
  <li>Android development</li>
  <li>Bluetooth Android API</li>
  <li>Java</li>
  <li>Eclipse IDE</li>
  <li>Matlab</li>
  <li>Microsoft Office</li>
  <li>Presentation</li>
  <li>Teamwork</li>
  <li>Leadership</li>
</ul>

<p>Resources:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="/assets/pdf/2018-06-03_unicas_imcs_scos_user_manual.pdf">Android Bluetooth Ranging Presentation</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>dt</name></author><category term="Academic Projects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Course Project for “Localization Navigation and Smart Mobility” Politecnico di Milano - Academic Year 2011/2012 As a student of Politecnico di Milano, I and other teammates developed this project inside the master course “Localization Navigation and Smart Mobility” held by Prof. Monica Nicoli. The project is an Android application. It estimates the distance between mobile terminals doing bluetooth measurements. Acquired and consolidated skills: Localization systems Bluetooth Android development Bluetooth Android API Java Eclipse IDE Matlab Microsoft Office Presentation Teamwork Leadership Resources: Android Bluetooth Ranging Presentation]]></summary></entry></feed>