<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-02-06T11:08:22+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Diego Tuzi Website</title><subtitle>Diego Tuzi Telecomunication Engineer Personal Website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Is your network security prepared for post-pandemic world?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/07/29/webinar-testingforpostpandemicnetwork.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is your network security prepared for post-pandemic world?" /><published>2021-07-29T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-08-02T11:32:56+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/07/29/webinar-testingforpostpandemicnetwork</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/07/29/webinar-testingforpostpandemicnetwork.html"><![CDATA[#### Keysight Technologies Digital Event

I attended the Webinar "Is your network security prepared for post-pandemic world?". Amritam Putatunda held the webinar. He is a Technical Product Manager-Application for Security Ixia Solutions Group at Keysight Technologies.
Thanks to this webinar I had on overview about the Challenges in Distributed Networks and Security and Performance Test Methodologies.

<img src="/assets/img/2021-07-29-webinar-testingforpostpandemicnetwork.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="2021-07-29-webinar-testingforpostpandemicnetwork">

For further information about Keysight webinars visit the [Keysight Engineering Education Webinar Series](https://www.keysight.com/it/en/events/europe-middleeast-africa-india/webinars.html?partnerref=ON24referral) web page.

Acquired and consolidated skills:
* Challenges in Distributed Networks
* Security and Performance test methodologies in Distributed Networks

Resources:
* [Certificate of Attendance](/assets/pdf/2021-07-29-webinar-testingforpostpandemicnetwork.pdf)]]></content><author><name>dt</name></author><category term="Webinars" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Keysight Technologies Digital Event I attended the Webinar “Is your network security prepared for post-pandemic world?”. Amritam Putatunda held the webinar. He is a Technical Product Manager-Application for Security Ixia Solutions Group at Keysight Technologies. Thanks to this webinar I had on overview about the Challenges in Distributed Networks and Security and Performance Test Methodologies. For further information about Keysight webinars visit the Keysight Engineering Education Webinar Series web page. Acquired and consolidated skills: Challenges in Distributed Networks Security and Performance test methodologies in Distributed Networks Resources: Certificate of Attendance]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Network simulation for public safety MANET Radios</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/07/22/webinar-netsim-pubsafe-manet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Network simulation for public safety MANET Radios" /><published>2021-07-22T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-08-01T13:04:18+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/07/22/webinar-netsim-pubsafe-manet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/07/22/webinar-netsim-pubsafe-manet.html"><![CDATA[#### Keysight Technologies Digital Event

I attended the Webinar "Network simulation for public safety MANET Radios". Vishal Gupta held the webinar. He is a Segment Manager (India) and Solutions Architect at Keysight Technologies.
Thanks to this webinar I had on overview about MANET network testing. It was really interesting the common approaches for channel modeling. 

<img src="/assets/img/2021-07-22-webinar-netsim-pubsafe-manet.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="webinar-netsim-pubsafe-manet">

For further information about Keysight webinars visit the [Keysight Engineering Education Webinar Series](https://www.keysight.com/it/en/events/europe-middleeast-africa-india/webinars.html?partnerref=ON24referral) web page.

Acquired and consolidated skills:
* Statistical channel modeling, Stochastic channel modeling, Geometry based stochastic modeling
* MANET network testing

Resources:
* [Certificate of Attendance](/assets/pdf/2021-07-22-webinar-netsim-pubsafe-manet.pdf)]]></content><author><name>dt</name></author><category term="Webinars" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Keysight Technologies Digital Event I attended the Webinar “Network simulation for public safety MANET Radios”. Vishal Gupta held the webinar. He is a Segment Manager (India) and Solutions Architect at Keysight Technologies. Thanks to this webinar I had on overview about MANET network testing. It was really interesting the common approaches for channel modeling. For further information about Keysight webinars visit the Keysight Engineering Education Webinar Series web page. Acquired and consolidated skills: Statistical channel modeling, Stochastic channel modeling, Geometry based stochastic modeling MANET network testing Resources: Certificate of Attendance]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Master Ultrahigh Bandwidth Signal Analysis with Time-domain Instrument in Aerospace and Defence</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/07/14/webinar-ultrahigh_bw_analysis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Master Ultrahigh Bandwidth Signal Analysis with Time-domain Instrument in Aerospace and Defence" /><published>2021-07-14T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-08-01T15:20:02+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/07/14/webinar-ultrahigh_bw_analysis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/07/14/webinar-ultrahigh_bw_analysis.html"><![CDATA[#### Keysight Technologies Digital Event

I attended the Webinar "Master Ultrahigh Bandwidth Signal Analysis with Time-domain Instrument in Aerospace and Defence". ABHIRAMA SHAMASUNDARA held the webinar. He is a Solutions Engineer for High Speed Digital test solutions at Keysight Technologies.
Thanks to this webinar I had on overview of the Aerospace and defence technology trends, Wideband signal analysis challenges and Time domain instrumentation for broadband signal analysis.

<img src="/assets/img/2021-07-14-webinar-ultrahigh_bw_analysis.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="webinar-ultrahigh_bw_analysis">

For further information about Keysight webinars visit the [Keysight Engineering Education Webinar Series](https://www.keysight.com/it/en/events/europe-middleeast-africa-india/webinars.html?partnerref=ON24referral) web page.

Acquired and consolidated skills:
* Technology trends: Radar, Electronic Warfare (EW), Satellite
* Wideband signal analysis

Resources:
* [Certificate of Attendance](/assets/pdf/2021-07-14-webinar-ultrahigh_bw_analysis.pdf)]]></content><author><name>dt</name></author><category term="Webinars" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Keysight Technologies Digital Event I attended the Webinar “Master Ultrahigh Bandwidth Signal Analysis with Time-domain Instrument in Aerospace and Defence”. ABHIRAMA SHAMASUNDARA held the webinar. He is a Solutions Engineer for High Speed Digital test solutions at Keysight Technologies. Thanks to this webinar I had on overview of the Aerospace and defence technology trends, Wideband signal analysis challenges and Time domain instrumentation for broadband signal analysis. For further information about Keysight webinars visit the Keysight Engineering Education Webinar Series web page. Acquired and consolidated skills: Technology trends: Radar, Electronic Warfare (EW), Satellite Wideband signal analysis Resources: Certificate of Attendance]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Field Testing at Millimeter-Wave with Wideband Analysis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/07/07/webinar-fieldtesting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Field Testing at Millimeter-Wave with Wideband Analysis" /><published>2021-07-07T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-07-23T13:35:12+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/07/07/webinar-fieldtesting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/07/07/webinar-fieldtesting.html"><![CDATA[#### Keysight Technologies Digital Event

I attended the Webinar "Field Testing at Millimeter-Wave with Wideband Analysis". Adesh Jain held the webinar. He is an Application Engineer inside RF&Microwave department at Keysight Technologies.
Thanks to this webinar I had on overview of Field Testing at Millimeter-Wave Wideband Analysis. Keysight developed a Fieldfox analyser able to detect signal up to 54 GHz and with 120 MHz bandwidth. It can be used in radar, satellite and 5GNR applications.

<img src="/assets/img/2021-07-07-webinar-keysight-fieldtesting.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="webinar-keysight-wifi6">

For further information about Keysight webinars visit the [Keysight Engineering Education Webinar Series](https://www.keysight.com/it/en/events/europe-middleeast-africa-india/webinars.html?partnerref=ON24referral) web page.

Acquired and consolidated skills:
* Millimeter-Wave
* Field Testing
* Satellite, Radar, 5GNR

Resources:
* [Certificate of Attendance](/assets/pdf/2021-07-07-webinar-keysight-fieldtesting.pdf)]]></content><author><name>dt</name></author><category term="Webinars" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Keysight Technologies Digital Event I attended the Webinar “Field Testing at Millimeter-Wave with Wideband Analysis”. Adesh Jain held the webinar. He is an Application Engineer inside RF&amp;Microwave department at Keysight Technologies. Thanks to this webinar I had on overview of Field Testing at Millimeter-Wave Wideband Analysis. Keysight developed a Fieldfox analyser able to detect signal up to 54 GHz and with 120 MHz bandwidth. It can be used in radar, satellite and 5GNR applications. For further information about Keysight webinars visit the Keysight Engineering Education Webinar Series web page. Acquired and consolidated skills: Millimeter-Wave Field Testing Satellite, Radar, 5GNR Resources: Certificate of Attendance]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wi-Fi 6 - Wait and See or Act Today</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/06/10/webinar-wifi6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wi-Fi 6 - Wait and See or Act Today" /><published>2021-06-10T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-11-11T20:07:24+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/06/10/webinar-wifi6</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/06/10/webinar-wifi6.html"><![CDATA[#### Keysight Technologies Digital Event

I attended the Webinar "Wi-Fi 6 - Wait and See or Act Today". Keshav Sudial held the webinar. Keshav Sudial is a Pre-Sales Application Engineer inside Network Solutions and Sales at Keysight Technologies.
Thanks to this webinar I had on overview of IEEE 802.11AX standard named "Wi-Fi 6".

<img src="/assets/img/2021-06-10-webinar-keysight-wifi6.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="webinar-keysight-wifi6">

For further information about Keysight webinars visit the [Keysight Engineering Education Webinar Series](https://www.keysight.com/it/en/events/europe-middleeast-africa-india/webinars.html?partnerref=ON24referral) web page.

Acquired and consolidated skills:
* IEEE 802.11AX Wi-Fi 6 overview
* Approach to Wi-Fi testing

Resources:
* [Certificate of Attendance](/assets/pdf/2021-06-10-webinar-keysight-wifi6.pdf)]]></content><author><name>dt</name></author><category term="Webinars" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Keysight Technologies Digital Event I attended the Webinar “Wi-Fi 6 - Wait and See or Act Today”. Keshav Sudial held the webinar. Keshav Sudial is a Pre-Sales Application Engineer inside Network Solutions and Sales at Keysight Technologies. Thanks to this webinar I had on overview of IEEE 802.11AX standard named “Wi-Fi 6”. For further information about Keysight webinars visit the Keysight Engineering Education Webinar Series web page. Acquired and consolidated skills: IEEE 802.11AX Wi-Fi 6 overview Approach to Wi-Fi testing Resources: Certificate of Attendance]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Seminar on “4G and 5G control signals, Stability analysis”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/05/24/unicas-electromagneticCompatibility_teaching1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seminar on “4G and 5G control signals, Stability analysis”" /><published>2021-05-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-11-11T20:07:19+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/05/24/unicas-electromagneticCompatibility_teaching1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/05/24/unicas-electromagneticCompatibility_teaching1.html"><![CDATA[#### Teaching activity for "Electromagnetic Compatibility: Modelling and Measurements" course
##### University of Cassino and Southern Lazio

At the end of my master degree thesis, I introduced my thesis work to students of the course "Electromagnetic Compatibility: Modelling and Measurements" held by Prof. Domenico Capriglione during the Academic Year 2020/2021. It was an interesting experience and I was really happy to explain my thesis work and to answer to the student's questions.
<img src="/assets/img/2021-05-24-unicas-electromagneticCompatibility_teaching1.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Thesis workflow image">

Acquired and consolidated skills:
* Human exposure to RF Fields (WHO/ICNIRP Guidelines, IEC measurement standards)
* NG-RAN, 5G New Radio (NR), 4G LTE
* 5G Dynamic spectrum Sharing
* Lab Instruments: Network Scanner R&S TSMA6, Spectrum Analyzer 
* R&S ROMES 4
* Matlab
* Python
* Libre Office Suite
* Public Speaking
* Presentation

Resources:
* [Presentation](/assets/pdf/2021-05-24-unicas-electromagneticCompatibility_teaching-5G.pdf)]]></content><author><name>dt</name></author><category term="Seminars for academic courses" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Teaching activity for “Electromagnetic Compatibility: Modelling and Measurements” course University of Cassino and Southern Lazio At the end of my master degree thesis, I introduced my thesis work to students of the course “Electromagnetic Compatibility: Modelling and Measurements” held by Prof. Domenico Capriglione during the Academic Year 2020/2021. It was an interesting experience and I was really happy to explain my thesis work and to answer to the student’s questions. Acquired and consolidated skills: Human exposure to RF Fields (WHO/ICNIRP Guidelines, IEC measurement standards) NG-RAN, 5G New Radio (NR), 4G LTE 5G Dynamic spectrum Sharing Lab Instruments: Network Scanner R&amp;S TSMA6, Spectrum Analyzer R&amp;S ROMES 4 Matlab Python Libre Office Suite Public Speaking Presentation Resources: Presentation]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Seminar on “EMF Human Exposure Measurements and Previsional Calculation for wireless systems”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/05/24/unicas-electromagneticCompatibility_teaching2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seminar on “EMF Human Exposure Measurements and Previsional Calculation for wireless systems”" /><published>2021-05-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-11-11T20:07:22+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/05/24/unicas-electromagneticCompatibility_teaching2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/05/24/unicas-electromagneticCompatibility_teaching2.html"><![CDATA[#### Teaching activity for "Electromagnetic Compatibility: Modelling and Measurements" course
##### University of Cassino and Southern Lazio

At the end of my master degree thesis, I organized and conducted a little seminar on "EMF Human Exposure Measurements and Previsional Calculation for wireless systems". I gave the seminar to "Electromagnetic Compatibility: Modelling and Measurements" students. I gave the seminar during the Academic Year 2020/2021. It was an interesting experience and I was really happy to explain part of my job and to answer to the student's questions.
<img src="/assets/img/2021-05-24-unicas-electromagneticCompatibility_teaching2.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Thesis workflow image">

Acquired and consolidated skills:
* D. Lgs. n. 259 del 2003
* Italian regulations about Human Exposure to EMF
* Broadband EMF Exposure Measurements
* EMF Previsional Calculation
* EMLAB
* Public Speaking
* Presentation

Resources:
* [Presentation](/assets/pdf/2021-05-24-unicas-electromagneticCompatibility_teaching-aie.pdf)]]></content><author><name>dt</name></author><category term="Seminars for academic courses" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Teaching activity for “Electromagnetic Compatibility: Modelling and Measurements” course University of Cassino and Southern Lazio At the end of my master degree thesis, I organized and conducted a little seminar on “EMF Human Exposure Measurements and Previsional Calculation for wireless systems”. I gave the seminar to “Electromagnetic Compatibility: Modelling and Measurements” students. I gave the seminar during the Academic Year 2020/2021. It was an interesting experience and I was really happy to explain part of my job and to answer to the student’s questions. Acquired and consolidated skills: D. Lgs. n. 259 del 2003 Italian regulations about Human Exposure to EMF Broadband EMF Exposure Measurements EMF Previsional Calculation EMLAB Public Speaking Presentation Resources: Presentation]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">4G and 5G control signals: Stability analysis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/04/29/unicas-thesis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4G and 5G control signals: Stability analysis" /><published>2021-04-29T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-02-06T10:58:21+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/04/29/unicas-thesis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/04/29/unicas-thesis.html"><![CDATA[#### Master of Science in Telecommunication Engineering
##### University of Cassino and Southern Lazio - Academic Year 2019/2020

As a student of University of Cassino and Southern Lazio, I ended my educational path with a thesis work entitled "4G and 5G control signals: Stability analysis". I worked on the thesis for 8 months. I started with an extensive research part followed by an experimental part. I, Prof. G. Miele (my Supervisor) and Prof. D. Capriglione, Prof. M.D. Migliore and Prof. G. Cerro (my Co-Supervisors) had several meetings during the work to address the activities.     

<img src="/assets/img/2021-04-29_unicas_thesis_scenario2.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Thesis workflow image">

It was an amazing experience. I'm very thankful to the Supervisors for received support and the availability during the thesis work.

Acquired and consolidated skills:
* Human exposure to RF Fields (WHO/ICNIRP Guidelines, IEC measurement standards)
* NG-RAN, 5G New Radio (NR), 4G LTE
* 5G Dynamic spectrum Sharing
* Lab Instruments: Network Scanner R&S TSMA6, Spectrum Analyzer 
* R&S ROMES 4
* Matlab
* Python
* Libre Office Suite
* Zotero
* Gimp
* Blackmagic Davinci Resolve
* Scientific writing
* Public speaking
* Presentation

Resources:
* [Thesis presentation](/assets/pdf/2021-04-29_unicas_master_thesis-slides.pdf)
* [Thesis document](/assets/pdf/2021-04-29_unicas_master_thesis.pdf)
* [Thesis video](https://youtu.be/0GfSU4wAMzQ)]]></content><author><name>dt</name></author><category term="Thesis works" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Master of Science in Telecommunication Engineering University of Cassino and Southern Lazio - Academic Year 2019/2020 As a student of University of Cassino and Southern Lazio, I ended my educational path with a thesis work entitled “4G and 5G control signals: Stability analysis”. I worked on the thesis for 8 months. I started with an extensive research part followed by an experimental part. I, Prof. G. Miele (my Supervisor) and Prof. D. Capriglione, Prof. M.D. Migliore and Prof. G. Cerro (my Co-Supervisors) had several meetings during the work to address the activities. It was an amazing experience. I’m very thankful to the Supervisors for received support and the availability during the thesis work. Acquired and consolidated skills: Human exposure to RF Fields (WHO/ICNIRP Guidelines, IEC measurement standards) NG-RAN, 5G New Radio (NR), 4G LTE 5G Dynamic spectrum Sharing Lab Instruments: Network Scanner R&amp;S TSMA6, Spectrum Analyzer R&amp;S ROMES 4 Matlab Python Libre Office Suite Zotero Gimp Blackmagic Davinci Resolve Scientific writing Public speaking Presentation Resources: Thesis presentation Thesis document Thesis video]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pspice simulations and Lab activities</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/12/unicas-ecs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pspice simulations and Lab activities" /><published>2020-06-12T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-11-11T20:07:14+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/06/12/unicas-ecs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/12/unicas-ecs.html"><![CDATA[#### Course reports for "Electronics for Communication Systems"
##### University of Cassino and Southern Lazio - Academic Year 2018/2019

As a student of University of Cassino and Southern Lazio, I realized several reports inside the master course "Electronics for Communication Systems" held by Prof. G. Busatto and Prof. C. Abbate.

<img src="/assets/img/2020-06-12-unicas-ecs.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="lab-example">

Acquired and consolidated skills:
* [Pspice](https://www.pspice.com/)
* Matlab
* Labs instruments: Power Supply, RF Signal Generator, Oscilloscope, Network Analyzer, Spectrum Analyzer 
* Writing reports

Resources:
* [The matching networks](/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_1_the_matching_network.pdf)
* [Wide band Cascode amplifier](/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_2_cascode_amplifier.pdf)
* [Low noise amplifier for FM receiver](/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_3_lna.pdf)
* [Tuned amplifier with variable tuning frequency](/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_4_tuned_amplifier_LO.pdf)
* [Design and PSPICE Simulation of the local oscillator](/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_5_LO.pdf)
* [Experimental Verification of a Low Noise Amplifier for FM receivers](/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_6_exp_LNA.pdf)
* [Experimental characterization of a tuned amplifier with variable tuning frequency](/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_7_exp_tuned_amplifier_LO.pdf)
* [Design and PSPICE simulation of a Mixer](/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_8_mixer.pdf)
* [Experimental characterization of a Low Noise Amplifier for FM receivers](/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_9_exp_mixer.pdf)
* [Experimental characterization of the integrated PLL (HCF4046B)](/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_10_exp_pll.pdf)
* [Simulation of a class AB RF Power amplifier](/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_11_classAB.pdf)
* [Experimental activity with a FM demodulator](/assets/pdf/2020-06-12_unicas_ecs_12_exp_demFM.pdf)]]></content><author><name>dt</name></author><category term="Academic Projects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Course reports for “Electronics for Communication Systems” University of Cassino and Southern Lazio - Academic Year 2018/2019 As a student of University of Cassino and Southern Lazio, I realized several reports inside the master course “Electronics for Communication Systems” held by Prof. G. Busatto and Prof. C. Abbate. Acquired and consolidated skills: Pspice Matlab Labs instruments: Power Supply, RF Signal Generator, Oscilloscope, Network Analyzer, Spectrum Analyzer Writing reports Resources: The matching networks Wide band Cascode amplifier Low noise amplifier for FM receiver Tuned amplifier with variable tuning frequency Design and PSPICE Simulation of the local oscillator Experimental Verification of a Low Noise Amplifier for FM receivers Experimental characterization of a tuned amplifier with variable tuning frequency Design and PSPICE simulation of a Mixer Experimental characterization of a Low Noise Amplifier for FM receivers Experimental characterization of the integrated PLL (HCF4046B) Simulation of a class AB RF Power amplifier Experimental activity with a FM demodulator]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Spectrum Characterization and Occupancy Sensing (SCOS) application</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/13/unicas-imcs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spectrum Characterization and Occupancy Sensing (SCOS) application" /><published>2018-06-13T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-11-11T20:07:12+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/06/13/unicas-imcs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/06/13/unicas-imcs.html"><![CDATA[#### Course Project for "Instrumentation and Measurements for Communication Systems"
##### University of Cassino and Southern Lazio - Academic Year 2018/2019

As a student of University of Cassino and Southern Lazio, I and other teammates developed this project inside the master course "Instrumentation and Measurements for Communication Systems" held by Prof. Gianfranco Miele.
The project is a “Spectrum Characterization and Occupancy Sensing (SCOS)” application. It uses two of Ettus USRP E310 (embedded SDR) controlled by GNU Radio and Matlab.

<img src="/assets/img/2018-06-13-unicas-imcs.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="scos gui">

Acquired and consolidated skills:
* [GNU Radio](https://www.gnuradio.org/)
* Software Defined Radio (SDR)
* [Ettus USRP E310](https://www.ettus.com/all-products/e310/)
* Matlab GUI
* Presentation
* Teamwork
* Leadership

Resources:
* [SCOS User Manual](/assets/pdf/2018-06-03_unicas_imcs_scos_user_manual.pdf)]]></content><author><name>dt</name></author><category term="Academic Projects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Course Project for “Instrumentation and Measurements for Communication Systems” University of Cassino and Southern Lazio - Academic Year 2018/2019 As a student of University of Cassino and Southern Lazio, I and other teammates developed this project inside the master course “Instrumentation and Measurements for Communication Systems” held by Prof. Gianfranco Miele. The project is a “Spectrum Characterization and Occupancy Sensing (SCOS)” application. It uses two of Ettus USRP E310 (embedded SDR) controlled by GNU Radio and Matlab. Acquired and consolidated skills: GNU Radio Software Defined Radio (SDR) Ettus USRP E310 Matlab GUI Presentation Teamwork Leadership Resources: SCOS User Manual]]></summary></entry></feed>